{
    "questions": [
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "The area of Europe where the Vikings came from is called?",
            "a": "Mesopotamia",
            "b": "Valhalla",
            "c": "The Tundra",
            "d": "Scandinavia",
            "correct": "Scandinavia"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What were Vikings also called?",
            "a": "Norsemen",
            "b": "Sheep",
            "c": "Pilgrims",
            "d": "Monks",
            "correct": "Norsemen"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "Vikings could be described as?",
            "a": "Astronauts",
            "b": "Deep sea fishermen",
            "c": "Bean farmers",
            "d": "Raiders",
            "correct": "Raiders"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What abilities are Vikings best known for?",
            "a": "Writing",
            "b": "Ship Building and Sailing",
            "c": "Reading",
            "d": "Mathematics",
            "correct": "Ship Building and Sailing"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What would craftworkers carve into wood to be placed on ships?",
            "a": "Dragon Heads",
            "b": "Tools",
            "c": "Armor",
            "d": "Banners",
            "correct": "Dragon Heads"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What would vikings call it when they went raiding?",
            "a": "Pleasant",
            "b": "Good times",
            "c": "To go a stealing",
            "d": "To go a viking",
            "correct": "To go a viking"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What were the fiercest Viking warriors called?",
            "a": "Ragers",
            "b": "Celts",
            "c": "Navy Seals",
            "d": "Beserkers",
            "correct": "Beserkers"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "Why was farmland scarse in the Viking homelands?",
            "a": "Too many people",
            "b": "Wolves owned the countryside",
            "c": "Many mountains",
            "d": "High winds",
            "correct": "Many mountains"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "Where were Viking farms located?",
            "a": "Underground using candles as light sources",
            "b": "On floating platforms in the ocean",
            "c": "In dedicated rooms of their homes",
            "d": "In between fjords and mountains",
            "correct": "In between fjords and mountains"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "What were the Viking alphabet letters called?",
            "a": "Stick figures",
            "b": "Runes",
            "c": "Symbols",
            "d": "Ode to Thunder",
            "correct": "Runes"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "question": "How did many Europeans feel about Vikings?",
            "a": "They wanted to adopt the Viking culture",
            "b": "They feared Vikings",
            "c": "They loved Vikings",
            "d": "They welcomed Vikings into their homes",
            "correct": "They feared Vikings"
        },
        {
            "a": "Digital maps",
            "c": "GPS",
            "b": "A compass",
            "d": "The sun and the stars",
            "question": "The Vikings navigated by using what?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "The sun and the stars"
        },
        {
            "a": "Sweden",
            "c": "Greenland",
            "b": "Constantinople",
            "d": "Mexico",
            "question": "After being banished from Iceland, Eric the Red went to?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "Greenland"
        },
        {
            "a": "To teach to talk",
            "c": "To hunt rats",
            "b": "To help them if they got lost",
            "d": "As loyal companions",
            "question": "Why did Vikings take birds to sea?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "To help them if they got lost"
        },
        {
            "a": "Philosopher",
            "c": "Emperor",
            "b": "Scientist",
            "d": "Explorer",
            "question": "Leif Ericson is famous for being a?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "Explorer"
        },
        {
            "a": "To attract settlers",
            "c": "It matched the environment found in Greenland",
            "b": "It was selected randomly",
            "d": "Eric the Red's daughter liked the name",
            "question": "Why was Greenland given its name?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "To attract settlers"
        },
        {
            "a": "From the Big Bang",
            "c": "By the trees",
            "b": "By the goddess of love",
            "d": "From ice, mist and snow",
            "question": "How was the world created according to Norse Mythology?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "From ice, mist and snow"
        },
        {
            "a": "Play tiddly winks",
            "c": "Listen to harp music",
            "b": "Sit in hot tubs",
            "d": "Battle by day and feast at night",
            "question": "What do Odin and the warriors do in Valhalla?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "Battle by day and feast at night"
        },
        {
            "a": "Thursday",
            "c": "Friday",
            "b": "Monday",
            "d": "Tuesday",
            "question": "What weekday is named after Thor, the Viking god of Thunder?",
            "topic": "Vikings",
            "correct": "Thursday"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What is a surplus?",
            "a": "Extra supply of something",
            "b": "Not enough of something",
            "c": "An additional man",
            "d": "A measure of distance",
            "correct": "Extra supply of something"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What is a colony?",
            "a": "Part of the human body",
            "b": "An unowned territory",
            "c": "A body of water",
            "d": "Territory settled by people of a country and controlled by that country",
            "correct": "Territory settled by people of a country and controlled by that country"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What is an import?",
            "a": "bringing goods into a country from another location",
            "b": "sending goods to another location",
            "c": "an item of great priority",
            "d": "a dock for boats",
            "correct": "bringing goods into a country from another location"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What is an export?",
            "a": "bringing goods into a country from another location",
            "b": "sending goods to another location in order to sell them",
            "c": "an item of great priority",
            "d": "a dock for boats",
            "correct": "sending goods to another location in order to sell them"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "An apprentice is?",
            "a": "A reality tv star",
            "b": "A ships captain",
            "c": "An expert in their respective field",
            "d": "someone who is learning a trade by working with someone who is skilled in that field",
            "correct": "someone who is learning a trade by working with someone who is skilled in that field"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "A merchant is?",
            "a": "A software developer",
            "b": "An expert in marketing",
            "c": "A very skilled musician",
            "d": "a person who buys and sells goods",
            "correct": "a person who buys and sells goods"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "Why did the Puritans come to the new world?",
            "a": "For wealth",
            "b": "Because yolo",
            "c": "In search of textiles to make new clothing",
            "d": "In search of religious freedom",
            "correct": "In search of religious freedom"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "Why is it difficult to grow crops in New England?",
            "a": "Lack of rain",
            "b": "New England is a desert",
            "c": "It is too windy",
            "d": "Long cold winters and poor soil",
            "correct": "Long cold winters and poor soil"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What were the New England colonists well known for?",
            "a": "Being baseball fans",
            "b": "Being awesome",
            "c": "Being expert shipbuilders",
            "d": "Being very good at making clothing",
            "correct": "Being expert shipbuilders"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "Why did the Quakers live?",
            "a": "China",
            "b": "India",
            "c": "California",
            "d": "Mid-Atlantic Colonies",
            "correct": "Mid-Atlantic Colonies"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "When did farmers start using the plow?",
            "a": "865",
            "b": "1975",
            "c": "After the civil war",
            "d": "During colonial times",
            "correct": "During colonial times"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "Why were market towns built near rivers or waterways?",
            "a": "People enjoy fishing",
            "b": "To ensure there were enough beaches for visitors",
            "c": "People enjoyed the weather near the water",
            "d": "To allow for easy transportation of goods",
            "correct": "To allow for easy transportation of goods"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What is a cash crop?",
            "a": "A crop grown for personal use",
            "b": "A crop that is expensive to produce",
            "c": "A crop that is inexpensive to produce",
            "d": "A crop that is grown only for money and not for personal use",
            "correct": "A crop that is grown only for money and not for personal use"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What were the 3 main cash crops of the Southern Colonies?",
            "a": "tobacco, indigo and cotton",
            "b": "corn, maze, and rice",
            "c": "rice, beans and apples",
            "d": "oranges, apples and blueberries",
            "correct": "tobacco, indigo and cotton"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What 2 groups did most of the hard labor on Southern Plantations?",
            "a": "Proletariat and bourgeoisie",
            "b": "Carpet baggers and soldiers",
            "c": "Explorers and tradesmen",
            "d": "Indentured servants and slaves",
            "correct": "Indentured servants and slaves"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "What did life in the Southern Colonies focus on?",
            "a": "Fun and pleasure",
            "b": "Mining and Hunting",
            "c": "Fishing and Baking",
            "d": "Farming and raising crops",
            "correct": "Farming and raising crops"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "The New England colonists depended on their natural resources to survive.",
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False",
            "correct": "True"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "The Puritans believed it was wrong to fight for any reason.",
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False",
            "correct": "False"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "The Native Americans traded furs in exchange for other goods such as metal pots and weapons.",
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False",
            "correct": "True"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "The Southern Colonies became known as the Bread Basket Colonies.",
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False",
            "correct": "False"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Colonies",
            "question": "Many skilled craftsmen and artisans lived in the Mid-Atlantic Colonies.",
            "a": "True",
            "b": "False",
            "correct": "True"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "The land bridge that connected Asia and North America is called?",
            "a": "The bridge to nowhere",
            "b": "Rainbow Bridge",
            "c": "Bridge over the River Kwai",
            "d": "Berginia",
            "correct": "Berginia"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Who lived in Beringia?",
            "a": "Elephants",
            "b": "Dolphins",
            "c": "Software Engineers",
            "d": "Hunter-Gatherers",
            "correct": "Hunter-Gatherers"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "The earliest inhabitants of the US land mass came from?",
            "a": "Asia",
            "b": "Australia",
            "c": "Bolivia",
            "d": "Mars",
            "correct": "Asia"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "The first people of Americas to learn how to grow crops were from?",
            "a": "Mexico",
            "b": "East India",
            "c": "New Zealand",
            "d": "New York",
            "correct": "Mexico"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What is an igloo?",
            "a": "A vacation spot",
            "b": "A bridge between Asia and North America",
            "c": "A cold weather animal",
            "d": "a dome shaped shelter made from snow blocks",
            "correct": "a dome shaped shelter made from snow blocks"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What is a kyak?",
            "a": "The bridge to nowhere",
            "b": "A cousin to a creeper",
            "c": "a special Inuit canoe made out of animal hide",
            "d": "A light tank",
            "correct": "a special Inuit canoe made out of animal hide"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What is another name for Anasazi?",
            "a": "sub lurkers",
            "b": "slave drivers",
            "c": "cliff dwellers",
            "d": "dog breeders",
            "correct": "cliff dwellers"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Where did the Anasazi live?",
            "a": "Florida",
            "b": "3 sides",
            "c": "Four Corners",
            "d": "Hawaii",
            "correct": "Four Corners"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What is a kyak?",
            "a": "The bridge to nowhere",
            "b": "A cousin to a creeper",
            "c": "a special Inuit canoe made out of animal hide",
            "d": "A light tank",
            "correct": "a special Inuit canoe made out of animal hide"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Mound builders stayed in one place because they were?",
            "a": "Lazy",
            "b": "Princesses",
            "c": "Sloth Like",
            "d": "Farmers",
            "correct": "Farmers"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Because they had no immunities to germs from Europe what happened to Native Americans?",
            "a": "They died rapidly",
            "b": "They lived long",
            "c": "They colonized the moon",
            "d": "They bred cows",
            "correct": "They died rapidly"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Where did the Hopi build their villages?",
            "a": "Atlantic Ocean",
            "b": "deep forests",
            "c": "high mesas",
            "d": "swamp land",
            "correct": "high mesas"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "The Navajo and Apache migrated to the Southwest from where?",
            "a": "Atlantic Ocean",
            "b": "Mexico",
            "c": "Boliva",
            "d": "Northern Canada",
            "correct": "Northern Canada"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Who were the ancestors of the Creeks?",
            "a": "ditch diggers",
            "b": "pack carriers",
            "c": "little whiners",
            "d": "mound builders",
            "correct": "mound builders"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Where did the Seminole Nation live?",
            "a": "Washington",
            "b": "New York",
            "c": "Florida",
            "d": "California",
            "correct": "Florida"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What did the 7 sides of the Cherokee nation represent?",
            "a": "Eternal Fairness",
            "b": "Forced Slavery",
            "c": "The Groups Clans",
            "d": "Princess Elsa",
            "correct": "The Groups Clans"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "Who wrote symbols for writing Cherokee?",
            "a": "Pocohontas",
            "b": "Elsa",
            "c": "Sequoyah",
            "d": "Elizabeth Warren",
            "correct": "Sequoyah"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What were the 3 sisters?",
            "a": "lots of fun",
            "b": "naggy",
            "c": "annoying",
            "d": "Iroquois crops",
            "correct": "Iroquois crops"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What type of houses did the Iroquois live in?",
            "a": "short houses",
            "b": "wide houses",
            "c": "tall houses",
            "d": "long houses",
            "correct": "long houses"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "The Mohawk and Seneca were part of what Confederacy?",
            "a": "Southern States",
            "b": "Viking Lands",
            "c": "South American",
            "d": "Iroquois",
            "correct": "Iroquois"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Native Americans",
            "question": "What is synomyous with the saying smoking the peace pipe?",
            "a": "Getting amped up",
            "b": "breaking stuff",
            "c": "starting a war",
            "d": "sitting down and talking calmly",
            "correct": "sitting down and talking calmly"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Test",
            "question": "Is testing value added?",
            "correct": "yes",
            "a": "yes",
            "b": "no",
            "c": "whatevs",
            "d": "not so much"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Test",
            "question": "What level of tests test at a method level",
            "correct": "unit test",
            "a": "unit test",
            "b": "functional test",
            "c": "regression test",
            "d": "user acceptance test"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "What is the order of planets from the sun?",
            "correct": "Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, Pluto",
            "a": "Venus, Earth, Mars, Pluto, Saturn, Andramoda 7, Uranus, Neptune, Jupiter",
            "b": "Mars, Venus, Earth, Mercury, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, Pluto",
            "c": "Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, Pluto",
            "d": "Mars, Venus, Earth, Jupiter, Sheldon, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, Pluto"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "What galaxy is Earth in?",
            "correct": "Milky Way",
            "a": "Andromeda",
            "b": "Nexus",
            "c": "Milky Way",
            "d": "Lateralus"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "What do the planets orbit around?",
            "correct": "The Sun",
            "a": "The Earth",
            "b": "The center of the universe",
            "c": "The polar axis",
            "d": "The Sun"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "What are the outer planets called?",
            "correct": "Gas Giants",
            "a": "Dwarf Planets",
            "b": "Colossal Orbs",
            "c": "Gas Giants",
            "d": "Meteoroids"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "The middle planets are mostly made of?",
            "correct": "rock",
            "a": "water",
            "b": "gas",
            "c": "rock",
            "d": "steel"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "How long does it take Earth to orbit on it's axis?",
            "correct": "24 hours",
            "a": "12 hours",
            "b": "10 hours",
            "c": "20 hours",
            "d": "24 hours"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "What are the phases of the moon?",
            "correct": "full moon, half moon, and crescent moon",
            "a": "full moon, 25% moon, and half moon",
            "b": "full moon, half full moon, and crescent moon",
            "c": "full moon, half moon, and crescent moon",
            "d": "whole moon, half moon, and 25% moon"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "A constellation is a group of?",
            "correct": "stars",
            "a": "planets",
            "b": "comets",
            "c": "fireflies",
            "d": "stars"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "A meteoroid is made of?",
            "correct": "rock, metal and ice",
            "a": "rock, steel and gas",
            "b": "lava, rock and water",
            "c": "rock, metal and ice",
            "d": "snow, fire and water"
        },
        {
            "topic": "Astronomy",
            "question": "How many tails does a comet have?",
            "correct": "2",
            "a": "1",
            "b": "3",
            "c": "4",
            "d": "2"
        }
    ]
}